<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.5.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-08-03T20:43:44-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">George Shaw Jr.</title><subtitle>Doctoral Candidate in the College of Information and Communication at the University of South Carolina.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Teaching Philosophy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/teachingphilsophy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Teaching Philosophy" /><published>2017-08-03T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-08-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/teachingphilsophy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/teachingphilsophy/">&lt;p&gt;My current thoughts on teaching and pedagogy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;teaching-philosophy&quot;&gt;Teaching Philosophy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that teaching is a reflection of your positionality.  Your educational, personal, spiritual, and/or social ideologies are reflected in you as a teacher.   I believe teaching involves creating life-long learners, invoking critical analysis, and fostering a passion for curiosity.  Through these concepts, I demonstrate my positionality but I do not create biases by factually claiming that my perspective is law.  However, I believe my credibility is shown through my knowledge, preparation, and passion for what I teach.  As a teacher, I believe that you cannot create a permanent label of who you are because different situations require different personas.  Depending on the circumstances, you have to play the role of educator, authoritarian, entertainer, life coach, and/or facilitator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning can be defined as many things based on the academic domain and desired outcome.  However, I think learning signifies the acquisition of new knowledge, skills, and perspectives regarding the world that we exist in.  Learning is not always static and as information and communication technologies (ICTs) continue to be integrated into the fabric of society, learning must reflect the innovative and evolving qualities of ICTs.  Learning should be a mastery of concepts, understanding of critical theories that explain certain information seeking behaviors, and a way to impact society.  When students take my classes, I want them to become better critical thinkers, problem solvers, and opportunistic to situations that disrupts their comfort zone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have experience teaching introductory courses such as Introduction to Library and Information Science and Research Methods in Information Science.  As a Teaching Assistant (TA), I appreciated the ability to get a different perspective about teaching, content development, content delivery, classroom management, and assessment.  As I move forward in my academic career, I anticipate teaching more health literacy and health informatics related courses.  There are several methods that I employ and will continue to develop as a teacher.  I am a strong believer in tacit knowledge.  I think skills such as innovation, leadership, and understanding emotional intelligence are not always learned through teaching and textbooks, but developed through interactions in the classroom.  I expect all my students to adhere to three “principles”:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Respect&lt;/em&gt; - we all have difference experiences, beliefs, faiths, personalities, educational backgrounds, and family structures that has impacted our lives.  While me may not agree with others opinions and beliefs, it is imperative that we have an open mind and listen to others to foster a collegial and constructive learning environment.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Positive Attitude&lt;/em&gt; - The ebb and flow of learning can be emotionally draining and cognitively overwhelming.  I think a positive attitude helps with overcoming the daily difficulties that we encounter, particularly with the rigorous demands of academic life.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fun&lt;/em&gt; - I emphasize students to have fun with the content.  I suggest that they take ownership of the information/knowledge acquired, create new meaning, question what is considered truth, and think about how they can take what they have learned to address a social issue.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the classroom experience, face-to-face or online, is more than just giving students the knowledge and skills to help them develop their employable toolkit. I think it is a space and opportunity for students to safely explore their curiosity, understand their position as a change agent, and develop potential relationships with classmates that may span decades beyond their collegiate experience. Over the past five years, I have sharpened my ability to deliver course content efficiently and effectively, foster dialogue among students, utilize technology for teaching instructions, establish SMART learning objectives, and properly assess students’ progression in courses. However, I think as a teacher, you are never perfect and learning will forever be a part of the profession, as external factors will affect how we teach students. As a teacher, I don’t see myself as a beholder of knowledge because there is still so much about the world and various social phenomena that we don’t know. I see myself as the coach to teach, guide, and inspire students to not only discover new knowledge but emphatically pursue their passion.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>George Shaw</name></author><summary type="html">My current thoughts on teaching and pedagogy.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ASIS&amp;amp;T 2017 Update</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ASIST-2017/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ASIS&amp;T 2017 Update" /><published>2017-07-31T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-31T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ASIST-2017</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ASIST-2017/">&lt;p&gt;Update on ASIS&amp;amp;T 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;asist-2017&quot;&gt;ASIS&amp;amp;T 2017&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Computational Content Analysis of Negative Tweets for Obesity, Diet, Diabetes, and Exercise”, was accepted for the ASIST 2017 in Crystal City, VA.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>George Shaw</name></author><summary type="html">Update on ASIS&amp;amp;T 2017</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">AMCIS 2017</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/AMCIS-2017/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AMCIS 2017" /><published>2017-07-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/%20AMCIS-2017</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/AMCIS-2017/">&lt;p&gt;Update on AMCIS 2017 in Boston, MA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;amcis-2017-update&quot;&gt;AMCIS 2017 Update&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been invited to attend the AMCIS 2017  Doctoral Consortium in Boston, MA.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>George Shaw Jr.</name></author><summary type="html">Update on AMCIS 2017 in Boston, MA.</summary></entry></feed>